Oluwafemi Laizer

5, Dele Oguntebi Street, Command, Ipaja, Lagos State, Nigeria.

Mobile: +2348164577260, 09087368137.

E-mail: femilaizer@gmail.com, olaizer@ikejaelectric.com

Profile Summary

A talented, responsible and self-motivated Electrical Electronic Engineer with experience in the power sector and in computer system operating environment. Capable at planning, motivating team members, monitoring the team performance and achievement towards organizational goals. I have ability to identify operational challenges and the methods to solving them. I have a customer-focused approach to work, and strong drive to see work through to completion.

Career Objective

Seeking to serve with excellence and focus to work with team of skilled professionals to fulfill the vision of the organization and improve my career and personal skills.

Education

B.Eng – Electrical Electronic Engineering.
Ekiti State University Ado – Ekiti, Ekiti State.

May 2009 - Sept. 2015

Skill Certification

• Executive Dashboards, Business Data Analysis and In-depth Excel. Nov. 2018 UrBizEdge Training Centre, Lagos State.

Managing Safely (Awaiting).
Institution of Occupational Safety and Health (IOSH)
Hybrid Group Training Centre, Lagos State.

Nov. 2019

Operational Skills

- Proficient in Office Suite, Microsoft Excel.
- Quality reporting and presentation
- Understands safety ethics for field activities and industrial operations.
- Understands installation of meters, electrical and electronic drawings and designs.

Additional Skills

- Proficient in HTML, CSS and JavaScript programming.
- AUTOCAD drawing, MATLAB and other computer base systems modules.

Key Strength

- Active listening and critical thinking.
- Ability to innovate, learn fast and communicate effectively.
- Paying attention to details.
- Ability to work under minimal supervision.
- Ability to make decision for operation effectiveness.
- Providing prompt report and complete resolution to general requests.

• Willingness to learn new skills and adapt to work environment.

Employment History

IKEJA ELECTRIC PLC, LAGOS.

Nov. 2017 - Present

Post Held: Non Maximum Demand Metering Revenue (Officer) Job role includes but not limited to:

Analyzing and interpreting customers' complaints by using statistical techniques and collected data to resolve it.

Supervise Installations and provide quality assurance before commissioning.

Draft daily installation plan and provide quality and certification report.

Train field staff on business operations and enforce compliance with management system and company policies.

Experience gained:

Customers' relation approach and persuasive communication skills.

Electrical Installations and Safety Culture.

Leadership skills and business acumen for resource and time management.

Achievement:

As a team, we metered prime and bilateral power customers.

Reduced customers' complaint on CRM to the barest minimum.

We were able to close out DFM meter installation in the network.

As a team, we were able to reduce the commercial and collection losses which increased the collection efficiency and improved revenue quarterly.

NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC).

April 2016 – April 2017

Post Held: Mathematics Teacher and Computer Operator.

Experience gained:

Effective communication and problem solving.

Computer instructions and operations.

MINL Nigeria LTD, ISOLO, OSHODI, LAGOS.

May 2014 - Sept. 2014

Post Held: Industrial Trainee

Duty: To carryout control, connections in the factory.

Experience gained:

Building of busbar panel for motor.

Troubleshooting and repair of electrical equipment.

Maintenance of production machine.

Hobbies and Interests

I enjoy reading, learning new skills, travelling and socializing with family and friends.

Referees

Available on request.